Ankit Kumar Roshan

Passionate front-end developer with 2 years of industry experience in web application development. Involved in the core team, contributing to all phases of product development that include definition, design, scoping, planning, implementation, and testing of new features.

akr.99799@gmail.com Linkedin Github Portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Appointy IT PVT LTD, Bhopal — Software Developer

August 2021 - PRESENT

- Provide clean and efficient code review within the team.
- Collaborate with internal teams to develop, enhance and fix product features, ensuring the best possible user experience.
- Work in an Agile-driven environment, effectively maintaining project timelines and utilizing available resources.
- Optimize code to reduce application latency and enhance performance.
- Optimize web accessibility throughout the application.

Appointy IT PVT LTD, Bhopal — Software Developer Intern

May 2021 - July 2021

- Developed a feature that displays the respective location in search results and Google Maps when a customer searches for a zip code.
- Developed and optimized web components.
- Gained experience in unit testing and end-to-end testing of the application to measure its effectiveness.

EDUCATION

Vellore Institute Of Technology, Vellore — BTech

July 2017 - July 2021

Electronic And Communication

CGPA: 7.8

PROJECTS

Covid tracker — Link

COVID tracker is react based application that provides real-time statistics on a global scale, including total cases, recoveries, and deaths worldwide, as well as country-specific data.

Tech Stack: - React, Material-UI, Typescript, HTML/CSS

SKILLS

Reactjs

TypeScript, JavaScript

HTML, CSS

GraphQL, React-relay

Material-UI, Formik, Yup validation

Jest, Cypress.io

ACHIEVEMENTS

Secured Rank 3 in Ideathon-3.0, VIT Vellore.

First place in Foldscope: Hands-on Workshop and Image Acquisition Contest, VIT Vellore.

Core committee member in the Design department & Project Ullas - FEPSI, VIT Vellore.